Nyrell Leonor

Seattle, WA I (206) 661-2450 I nyrell.leonor2000@gmail.com I www.nyrellcl.com I Github I LinkedIn

SUMMARY

Front-end Developer skilled in creating user-friendly, responsive websites and applications using HTML, SCSS/SASS, and JavaScript/TypeScript, as well as frameworks such as React and NextJS. Personal experience in branding and have developed my own personal brand through various social media platforms, where I share my personal projects and insights on the latest trends and techniques in front-end development and design.

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

- Designed and developed multiple front-end applications using HTML, CSS, SCSS/SASS, and JavaScript/TypeScript, with experience in building responsive and dynamic user interfaces using React.js.
- Incorporated mobile-first responsive web design principles, and UI/UX best practices in my applications for creating intuitive and engaging user experiences.
- Developed multiple projects using Git for version control whilst focusing on maintaining high standards of code quality.
- Integrated front-end frameworks such as React and NextJS in my development process to enhance the scalability of applications and quality of user interfaces.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Logistics Specialist 09/2021 - 12/2022

Frontier Supply Chain Solutions Inc.

- Expanded the company's product database by contributing over 80+ new product codes.
- Cleared over 200+ commercial freight deliveries crossing state borders, with an average of approximately 10 deliveries a day.
- Communicated with commercial drivers and vendors to ensure accurate and timely delivery of goods ensuring clearance that took no longer than 2 days.

Sales Associate 11/2018 - 07/2020

Zara Inc.

- Streamlined check-out process by utilizing efficient floor maintenance techniques resulting in 50% increase in productivity amongst team members.
- Effectively increased productivity by 20% training new employees on daily store tasks and procedures.
- Delivered daily revenue consistently within budget parameters through effective shop organization & sales promotion during peak hours, amplified reach by 25%.

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

Website Portfolio

- Designed, developed, & hosted my own website portfolio using HTML, SCSS/SASS, JavaScript, Third Party API's - Swiper.js and typed.js.
- Incorporated Google Analytics A4 to monitor and increase website traffic by 200% and steadily increase weekly page views by 15%.

Front-End Projects

- Completed a series of Front-End challenges using various Front-End tools & languages such as HTML, CSS and SCSS/SASS, JavaScript, React.js, and Third Party API's
- Developed interactive and user-friendly web applications using React.js and SCSS/SASS that incorporated UI/UX design principles.

Github User Search App, To-Do List, Typing game - React, HTML, SCSS/SASS, Git & GitHub, API's

- Developed single page applications using ReactJS for front-end
- Used Third Party API's to manage and render data on the client side
- Deployed using Github Pages

Random Advice Generator- HTML, SCSS/SASS, JavaScript, Third Party API

- Developed a web application that generates a random advice that's called from an API database
- Used Git for version control
- Deployed using Github Pages

CSS Art - HTML, CSS, SCSS/SASS

- Developed multiple art projects using CSS, to strengthen CSS and design skills
- Used Git for version control and GitHub for continuous deployment

Mock Websites - HTML, SCSS/SASS, JavaScript, React, TailwindCSS, Third Party API

- Developed multiple front-end mock websites using design files and assets to simulate real world front-end practices
- Created documentation for each project to inform users and developer on the development journey
- Used Git for version control and Github Pages for deployment

EDUCATION

Shoreline Community College – Shoreline, WA

Purchasing, Procurement/Acquisitions and Contracts Management 09/2021 - 01/2022

Seattle Pacific University - Seattle, WA

Department of Psychology 09/2018 - 01/2019